EMMACULATE WAMBOI

Nairobi emmaculatewamboi@gmail.com | +254712589930 https://github.com/Ewamboi in https://www.linkedin.com/in/emmaculate

OBJECTIVE

Apply my professional competencies and technical skills diligently to achieve different goals set at institutional/organizational and/or corporate levels. Also, I target to get a wealth of technical skills and experience for my engagements that will position me to be competitively reliable in the job market.

EXPERIENCE

Independent Electoral and Boundaries Commission

2022 - 2022

- **Deputy Presiding Officer**
- o Collect and ensure security of all Election materials.
- o Oversee efficient and effective management of the election before, during and after the by election.
- Ensure good conduct of elections in the polling station.
- Counting, tallying and announcement of provisional results at the polling
- o station and delivering the same to the RO.
- Ensure safe custody of all entrusted documents, document handover of all election materials and equipment to the RO after the Election.
- o Assist in the training of polling/counting clerks.
- o Any other duties as assigned by the Returning Officer.

• CCI kenya 2021 - 2022

customer Care Agent

- o Answer inbound and outbound calls in a timely manner.
- Respond to Emails in the required time.
- o Evaluate customers problems and provide quick responses and accurate
- o Created rapport with customers by engaging the customers.
- o Ensured all the customers complaints are well taken care of by making proper escalatios when needed to.

• CSV Research 2021 - 2021

Data Analyst Intern (Remote)

- o Managed and updated the database on a day to day basis
- o Worked closely with the marketing team and came up with great marketing materials
- Developed powerpoint presentations on a day to day basis depending on the type of course that was being taught
- o Generation of weekly and monthly reports
- Managed a team of 10 people.

Key achievements

- Developed a client based database
- Managed to set up a personal website

Kenya National Bureau of Statistics

2019 - 2020

- Research Assistant
- o Administered the research questionnaire through PAPI.
- o Performed follow-up on responses and ensured any other useful information is collected for
- a validation
- o Recorded comments and questioondents that weren't adequately answered.
- Prepared and submitted daily reports to the supervisor
- o Provided research support and other duties as assigned by the supervisor.

Key achievements

o Assisted in data cleaning

Telkom Enterprise
2019 - 2019

Project management

- o Managed a group of sales representatives and contractors
- o Monitor progress and make adjustments when required
- o Ensure the right standards are met.
- o Develop and manage a detailed work schedule and work plan to meet the desired deadlines.
- o Provide project updates consistently to the stakeholders regarding the progress.

2021-20

- o Determine the project scope and objectives.
- o Assisted in marketing the product as we progressed.

• Safaricom limited 2018 - 2019

- sales and marketing Representative
- Provided product information and advice to customer
- Performed acquisition of tower building with clear documentation
- o Documented sales by creating and updating customer profiles.
- o Contributed in the increase of the monthly sales by 10%
- o Guided customers on the payment procedure and notified them on new producuct.
- o Contributed to team effort by accomplishing related results as needed.

EDUCATION

• UDACITY	2022
Data Analytics Nanodegree	
MACHAKOS UNIVERSITY	2018
Bsc in statistics and programming second class	
KAPKENDA GIRLS HIGH SCHOOL	2013
Highschool Certificate	
В	

SKILLS

- · Analytical and problem solving skills
- · Planning, time management and organizational skills
- · Communication and performance monitoring
- · Statistical Analysis
- · Python & SQL
- Data Visualization(Power BI, Tableau)
- · Statistical Programming languages
- · Microsoft Suit (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- · Google analytics
- · Attention to details
- Data Management
- HTML & CSS

PROJECTS

• WeRateDogs Twitter account

I analyzed the Twitter account which is dedicated to rating dogs. In this project, I mainly tested my data-wrangling skills. The project is available on my GitHub.https://github.com/Ewamboi

ACHIEVEMENTS & AWARDS

- Google Certification in Data Analytics
- Microsoft Database Fundamentals
- CISCO IT Essentials
- Udacity Nanodegree in data analytics

REFERENCE

• Upon request